Now let's talk about Amazon EMR.
Bây giờ hãy nói về Amazon EMR.
So EMR stands for Elastic MapReduce
EMR là viết tắt của Elastic MapReduce
and EMR helps you create Hadoop clusters
và giúp bạn tạo các cụm Hadoop
for doing big data on AWS.
để xử lý big data trên AWS.
This allows you to analyze
Điều này cho phép bạn phân tích
and process vast amount of data.
và xử lý lượng dữ liệu khổng lồ.
Anytime you would see anything related
Bất cứ khi nào bạn thấy điều gì liên quan
to big data clusters with Hadoop clusters,
đến các cụm big data với Hadoop,
then think Amazon EMR.
hãy nghĩ đến Amazon EMR.
These clusters have to be provisioned
Các cụm này cần được cấp phát
and they can be made of hundreds of EC2 instances.
và có thể gồm hàng trăm instance EC2.
Why would you use EMR?
Tại sao dùng EMR?
EMR comes bundled with a lot of tools
EMR đi kèm nhiều công cụ
that big data specialist use.
mà chuyên gia big data sử dụng.
For example, Apache Spark, or HBase,
Ví dụ Apache Spark, HBase,
or Presto, or Apache Flink.
Presto hay Apache Flink.
They're very difficult to set up,
Chúng rất khó thiết lập,
so Amazon EMR will take care of all the provisioning
vì vậy Amazon EMR lo việc cấp phát
and the configuration of these services for you.
và cấu hình các dịch vụ đó cho bạn.
You can also auto-scale your entire cluster
Bạn cũng có thể auto-scale toàn bộ cụm
and it's integrated with spot instances
và tích hợp spot instance
for you to benefit from price reductions.
để hưởng lợi giảm giá.
So the use cases of Amazon EMR
Các trường hợp dùng Amazon EMR
from an exam perspective are going to be
trong kỳ thi xoay quanh xử lý dữ liệu,
around data processing,
machine learning, web indexing và big data
doing machine learning, web indexing and big data
nhưng tất cả đều dùng công nghệ big data
but all of them using big data related technologies
như Hadoop, Spark, HBase, Presto, Flink...
such as Hadoop, Spark, HBase Preso Flink, and so on.
Amazon EMR gồm các cụm instance EC2
Amazon EMR is made of clusters of EC2 instances
với các loại node khác nhau.
and you have different kind of nodes.
Có Master Node
You have the Master Node.
quản lý cụm,
The Master Node manages the cluster,
điều phối và giám sát tình trạng
it will coordinate and manage the health
các node khác, và phải chạy liên tục.
of all your other nodes, and it must be long running.
Tiếp theo là Core Node, chạy tác vụ
Then you have the Core Node, they're here to run tasks
và lưu dữ liệu, cũng phải chạy liên tục.
and also store data, and they must be long running as well.
Sau đó là Task Node
Then you have this Task Node
chỉ dùng để chạy tác vụ.
which is there just to run tasks.
Thường bạn có thể dùng spot instance cho nó
Usually you can take spot instances for it
và task node là tùy chọn.
and using task node is optional.
Tùy chọn mua phụ thuộc vào nhu cầu.
The purchasing options really depends.
Nếu dùng EC2 on-demand
If you have the on-demand EC2 instance type
bạn có workload ổn định
then you're going to get reliable
và không bị chấm dứt.
predictable type of workloads
Nếu dùng reserved instance
and then will never be terminated.
(tối thiểu một năm),
If you use reserved instances,
bạn sẽ tiết kiệm chi phí lớn
and remember it's minimum one year of usage,
và EMR sẽ tự dùng RI nếu có.
then you're going to get big cost savings
Vì vậy Master Node
and EMR will automatically
và Core Node là ứng viên tốt cho RI.
use your reserved instances if possible.
Đối với spot instance, vì có thể bị thu hồi
Therefore, good candidates for reserved instances
nên ít tin cậy hơn nhưng rẻ.
are going to be the Master Node
Cách tốt để dùng spot instance
because it must be long running, and also the Core Nodes.
là áp dụng cho Task Node.
Regarding spot instances, because they can be terminated
Cuối cùng, về triển khai EMR,
they're less reliable but they're cheaper.
bạn có thể dùng cụm chạy lâu dài
A good way for you to leverage spot instances
phù hợp với reserved instance,
would be on Task Nodes.
hoặc cụm tạm thời
Finally, for EMR, in terms of deployment
chạy xong rồi xoá
you can have either long running clusters
khi phân tích hoàn tất.
which would make sense than using reserved instances,
Được rồi, bạn đã biết những gì cần thiết
or you can use transient temporary clusters to
cho Amazon EMR trong kỳ thi.
just do something and then tear it down
Hy vọng bạn thích,
once the analysis is done.
và hẹn gặp ở bài tiếp theo.